Álan Crístoffer e Sousa



Contact +33 6 20 48 95 86 acristoffers@startmail.com https://esousa.me

Languages

Portuguese (native) English (C1/C2) German (B2/C1) French (B2/C1)

Skills

C/C++
Control Theory
Data Analysis
Data Processing
Docker
Embedded Development
GUI Development
GitLab CI/CD
Go

Industrial Automation Linux/Unix Management Networked Communication Problem-solving Python Robotics

Rust SQL Shell (Bash, Zsh, Fish) System Analysis Teamwork Technical Communication Troubleshooting Web (HTML, CSS) Zig

Interests

Languages Programming Technology

Profile

Ph.D. in Industrial Automation and Master's in Electrical Engineering, I have conducted advanced research and worked as a **Mechatronics Engineer** and **Software Developer**, highlighting my abilities to **think critically**, **solve problems**, apply advanced techniques, and **implement solutions**.

Experience

04/2024- **Vitibot**

France

Development Engineer

- DevOps and CI/CD pipeline development for robotics software systems, ensuring robust versioning, testing, and deployment practices.
- Model Predictive Control (MPC) design and implementation for precise trajectory tracking and control in mobile robotic systems
- Comprehensive development of mobile robot functionality using C++ and ROS, including sensor integration, perception, and motion planning
- Real-time system diagnostics to ensure stability, safety, and reliability in autonomous operations
- Hands-on experience with robotic middleware and message-passing systems, enabling efficient and scalable communication across robotic modules

03/2021-09/2024 Université de Reims Champagne-Ardenne

France

Research Associate and Professor Assistant

- Communication of results through congress presentation and article publication.
- Test of solution in both simulations and real hardware using the **ROS** in conjunction with other technologies.
- Preparation and ministering of classes on technical subjects, like Android Development,
 System Analysis and Control, and ROS.

01/2017-12/2017 **DETEC**

Brazil

Founder Member

- Development of **embedded** software for an ammonia detector.
- Participation in TIM's AWS startup accelerator program.

03/2016-08/2016 **Acal BFi** Intern

Germany

• Design and production of a platform for measuring power loss within PFC circuit inductors' kernels, including **PCB design** and assembly, software development (embedded and **GUI**), and execution of tests.

Education

03/2021-09/2024 Ph.D. in Industrial Automation

Université de Reims Champagne-Ardenne, France

• Title: Enhancing Cyber-Physical System Security: Detection and Mitigation Strategies.

01/2020-12/2020 Master in Electrical Engineering

CEFET-MG/UFSJ, Braz

Development of a novel switching rule based on Region of Attraction to speed up the convergence of switched systems.

04/2013–12/2019 **Mechatronics Engineering**

CEFET-MG, Brazil

- Development of a platform to help students and researchers interface with different hardware using the same API (Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript).
- Tutoring of three Junior Scientific Initiation groups.
- · Student member of the Graduation Council.
- Exchange at Frankfurt University of Applied Sciences (Germany).
- Exchange at Université Joseph Fourier (France).
- 3^{rd} place in the Latin America **Robotic** Competition.
- 2^{rd} place in the National Instruments' MyRIO Competition.
- Tutoring of **C/C++** for Mechatronics and IT students.